CEARA CURRAN OWRE

1502 CUMBERLAND RD, CHAPEL HILL, NC 27514

cearacowre@gmail.com • 919-360-1681

github.com/Cabco19 • www.linkedin.com/in/ceara-owre-a0b361192/

Full-stack professional with strong web development and design skills and an extensive background in graphic design and fine arts. Recently completed the Coding Bootcamp at UNC-Chapel Hill demonstrating the ability to learn new skills with solid critical thinking abilities. Years of front-end web design and graphic design experience working in a variety of environments maintaining and designing websites. Managed from conception to completion large graphic design projects such as 40-page annual company booklets and bi-annual newsletters. With extensive experience in full stack development and a Bachelor of Arts in Fine Arts from St. Michael's College in Vermont, employers will find a team player and creative mind that enjoys problem solving and new challenges.

SKILLS WEB DEVELOPMENT

Highly proficient, extensive experience with HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, JQuery, Node.js, and UI Development Working knowledge of PHP

Proficient in Visual Studio Code, Git, Wordpress and FTP

DATABASE MANAGEMENT

Working knowledge of database design and management Proficient in MySQL and MongoDB

GRAPHIC DESIGN

Highly proficient, extensive experience with layout and design for print and web media Extensive knowledge of Adobe Creative Suite, including Photoshop, InDesign and Illustrator

Highly proficient, extensive experience with Windows Live Movie Maker

Synchronization of Powerpoint presentations and audio files to create video files

PROJECTS

Travelogue - A full stack web application that allows users to relive some of their greatest adventures.

· Technologies: Mongo, Heroku mLab, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, Axios, Express, Mongoose, React, Passport, React-Datepicker

Quintessential Curations - This App searches for artists or bands similar to a band that the user enjoys.

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Materialize, Firebase

Order A Burger - A restaurant App that lets users input the names of burgers they'd like to eat using CRUD (Create, Read, Update, and Delete) operations.

* Technologies: HTML, CSS, Axios, Express, JavaScript, MsSql

EXPERIENCE

Web Designer – The Rome Foundation (www.theromefoundation.org), Chapel Hill, NC 2007 - 2019

Maintained and managed website

Design online forms with payment gateway integration

· Created and designed online directory for Gastroenterologists (www.romegipsych.org)

2007 - 2019Graphic Designer – The Rome Foundation, Chapel Hill, NC

Designed semi-annual newsletter, and other promotional materials

Freelance Web Designer 2000 - 2019

· Clients include Five Spice Café and University Presbyterian Preschool

2003 - 2005Web Designer - Dept. of Slavic Languages and Literatures, UNC—Chapel Hill, NC Developed, designed and maintained web site including periodic updates

Responsible for design of all departmental communications materials

EDUCATION

UNC-Chapel Hill, Chapel Hill, NC 2019 - 2020

Coding Bootcamp Certificate

Champlain College, Burlington, VT

Web Page Development and Management Program

Market Makers, Burlington, VT

Desktop Publishing Certificate

Royal College of Art, London, England

Certificate of Study

Saint Michael's College, Colchester, VT

BA, Fine Arts